<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-adolph-luetgert</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87060190/1897-05-18/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Adolph+Luetgert</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          ACCUSED OF WIF.E MURDER;
          Adolph L. Luetgert of Chicago Arrested
          on Suspicion.
          Chicago, May 18. Adolph L. Luet
          gerjl, a well known manufacturer vraa
          arrested yesterday afternoon on tho
          chargo of having murdered his wife.
          Luetgert made an assignment about 10
          days ago, and about tho same time Mrs.
          Luetgert disappeared. It was at first
          supposed that she had committed sui
          cide, as a result Of her husband's
          failnro.

          Tho police claim to have direct
          evidence that Luetgert klljed his wife
          in tho basement of his sausage factory
          in Diversoy street, and that her body
          was destroyed with the object of hiding,
          all traces of tho crime.
          ho choked her to death
          or to insensibility that he then threw
          her into a vat containing a powerful
          acid, and completed his work by casting
          the body into an intonso firo.

          This is the direct chargo against tho
          prisoner. Tho main evidence in snp-
          Jiort of it aro two gold rings which be
          ouged to Mrs. Luetgort and which
          were found by the polico in a vat in tho
          sausage factory. Ono of tho rings
          found in tho vat was tho wedding ring
          of Mrs. Luetgert.
          On tho day following tho woman's
          disappearance Luetgert failed in busi
          ness, and tho sheriff took possession of
          the sausage factory.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063615/1897-07-20/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=-0.252,-0.075,1.504,1.504,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          WAS IT MRS. LUETGERT?
          cw lork Muu Clnlmn to Have Seen
          Her In ew Turk After Her
          Alleged Murder.
          New York. July 20. For more than two
          months the police of this city have been
          In possession of Information which. If true,
          and the circumstances indicate that It Is,
          will save the life of Adolph Luetgcrt. now
          In Jail In Chicago, charged with the murder
          of his wife. It Is. That Mrs. Luetgcrt was
          in this city on May 7, and this Is apparent
          ly conclusive evidence. A. W. C Grotty
          formerly lived in Chicago. He was well
          acquainted with Mrs. Luetgert. In fact,
          he had known her as Louise Blckncs. Ions
          before she became the wife of Luetgert.

          He noticed that she appeared
          somewhat excited, but paid no great at
          tention to It. He told her that since he
          had last seen her In Chicago ho had mar
          ried, and expected his wile hero oon,
          when he would be very glad to have Mr.
          Luetgert call.

          At the Occidental hotel. Broome street
          and the Bowery, the register fails to show
          thnt anybody by the name of Luetgert
          from Chicago stopped there during the first
          ten days of May
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016014/1897-08-07/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>
          
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1897-08-31/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=-0.284,-0.078,1.568,1.568,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          They have taked off five claims and he
          tells his wife to send up four friends
          whom he designates as quickly as pos
          sible to locate th adjoining properties
          the Jaw being that one man can locate
          only one claim.

          The result exceeds their expectations j i
          The experts reported that after belling j i
          the body in a 15 per cent solution of
          the potash for some length of time
          three and onehalfhours and under the I
          same circumstances as the state alleges
          Luetgert disintegrated the body of his
          wife the complete skeleton of the ca
          daver remained intact and the solu
          tion had but little effect upon the cloth.

          Luetgert was calm and composed
          when he was brought into court and
          he had apparently been greatly re I
          freshed by Sundays respite from the
          daily court room ordeal Assistant
          States Attorney McEwan formally
          opened the case for the state Op the
          wall close to the jury box were hung
          large maps of the Luetgert sausage
          factory the Luetgert home and all the
          surroundings of the place where it is i
          charged the prisoner killed his wife
          and then destroyed her body The at il
          torney for the state began with the
          disappearance of Mrs Luetgert on May
          1 and next described the visit on May.

          Luetgert who came in and ordered the
          boy to bed Before going to sleep the
          boy heard his father descending the
          back stairs toward the factory where
          he had slept for years Mr McEwan
          said it is cite theory of the state that
          Mrs Luetgert descended the stairs at
          the same tim andwent to the factory
          The boy did not hear her steps because
          she wore house slippers which made no
          noise Luetgert and his wife were seen
          in the alley in the rear of the house a
          few minutes later They were seen
          gong through a gate which led tb no
          place except the factory

          I reason which actuated Luetgert ac
          cording to the theory of the state was
          then described Mr ileEwon said Luet
          gert despised hs wife He had treated
          her with violence as the evidence of
          the state will show He had no affection
          for her and lived alone in the factory
          There the attorney said he had been
          visited by other women Judge Vincent
          objected to this statement but Judge
          Tuthill overruled the objection Mr
          McEwan paid a witness would testify
          that he KUV Luetgetri choke his wife in
          the chicken house back of the resdence
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059523/1897-10-01/ed-1/?sp=7&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=-0.278,-0.078,1.556,1.556,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Dr. Allport looked surprised, but re
          covering himself suddenly he obaerved:
          "Well, it might have been a monkey
          faced dog." This was greeted with a
          laugh in which Luetgert joined.
          It is likely that the cross fire of the
          experts will be kept up for nearly an
          other week. After they have finished
          Luetgert will be called. Attorney Vin
          cent does not believe that Luetgert's
          evidence is essential. In the opening
          statement he told the jury that the big
          sausage maker would talk to them
          from the witness stand, and he said
          yesterday he would not disappoint the
          jury.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063952/1897-10-23/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=-0.27,-0.077,1.539,1.539,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Luetgert Mnket Stnteinont Concern
          ing the Uaio-Sitoti Ito Mil Nut
          Kill Ilia Wife nml Hoc, Not
          Itnotr "here Sho 1 Will
          lis Tried Again Will Alk
          to lie Jlolrateil on Unit.
          Chicago, Oct 22. The Luetgert
          Jury has disagreed nnd been dis
          charged. It stood nine for conviction
          and three for acquittal.

          Last night Luetgert mndo the fol
          lowing statomunt under oath:
          "To tho Public Tho result of ny
          trinl Is a victory for mc becauso of the
          disagreement of tho Jury, but 1 nm
          very much disappointed nnd very
          much surprised thnt tho jury did nut
          bring in a verdict of not gulltv.
          "1 did not kill my wife, nnd do not
          know whoro she Is, but I nm sure thnt
          It is only a question of timo until hIio
          comes home.

          Counsel for Luetgert gave State's
          Attorney Dencon, notice thnt thoy
          would to-day make formal nppllen
          lion before Judge Tuthlll for the ad
          mission of tho prisonor to ball. Judgo
          Tutthlll will be naked to fix tho
          amount of ball ut 15,000, but Luet
          gert will enter court prepared to fur
          nish bond for 880,000, If noeeskary.
          State's Attornoy Dencon wns not pro
          pared to say whothor or not he would
          rosist the application.
          It Is quite probable that some pro so
          cutions for perjury will result from
          tho Luetgert ensa Whllo the state's
          attorney refused to affirm or dony
          this, It is given on tlrst-olnss authority
          that tho testimony of two of tho
          principal witnessed for the dofensu
          will bo laid beforo tho grand jury for
          an investigation.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85033781/1897-10-27/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife+witness&st=text&r=-0.305,-0.081,1.61,1.61,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          SCORES OF WITNESSES EXAMINED
          tate Wearfi a Net of Circumstantial Evi
          dence About the Prisoner Expert Teatl
          loony uu Hone Foil ml in the Middle Vat
          of the SauMtge Factory Allege! Appear
          ance or the MUliitf Woman In Varloin
          Place Perwoiiallty of the Prioner.
          Or the rJfiht of May 1 last Louisa
          Luetgert disappeared. At 8 o'clock
          Mary Siemmering. the servant girl, re
          tired for the night, leaving Mrs. Luet
          gert Etill about the house. A little later
          the boy Louis returned from a circus
          vhich had been exhibiting in the neigh
          borhood and found his mother sitting In
          a chair. It was then about 10 o'clock
          end he was sent to bed, having seen the
          last of his mother, perhaps forever. Mr.
          Luetgert came Into the house a little be
          fore the boy went to bed, and the latter
          left husband and wife together. At this
          roint the story diverges and the most
          erious trouble of A. L. Luetgert's life
          begins. At what hour Mrs. Luetgert
          left the house no one, save possibly her
          husband, knows. The following day
          Sunday members of the family knew
          that its mistress was gone. On the 17th
          day of May the climax came. The saus
          age maker, who had been almost a king
          among his neighbors, was dragged up
          the steps of the East Chicago avenue
          police station at about 2 o'clock In the
          afternoon.

          Mrs. Agatha Tosch, Luetgert's
          warm friend and proprietor of the sa
          loon which he patronized most, declared
          to the police she believed him guilty
          cf wife murder, and unexpectedly went
          on the stand and told how Luetgert had
          railed about his wife to her, and had
          eald he wished she were dead.

          On Monday, Aug. 20,
          Diedrich Bicknese, the first witness for
          the prosecution, was put on the stand
          Louis Luetgert, the 12-year-old son
          cf the prisoner, was one of the state's
          earliest witnesses. He recited the oc
          currences of the night of May 1, and
          told a powerful story for the prosecu
          tion, on cross-examination there was a
          rurprise for the state. The boy an
          nounced that at 2 o'clock in the morn
          ing of May 2, when, according to the j
          ytate, Mrs. Luetger's body was being
          destroyed in the vat, he heard a "rust
          ling" in the house, and a voice which I
          he believed was his mother's. Young i
          Luetgert acknowledged he had suddenly
          recollected this in the office of Luetgert's
          attorneys, and the state flatly charged
          that Luetgert's attorneys had manufact
          ured the evidence.

          After returning to the Jail Luetgert
          said: "I expected an acquittal. I
          thought I would be able to sleep at horn
          tonight. Hut we will try to get ball
          tomorrow. At any rate, the disagree
          ment only forces me to wait for my lib
          erty a little while. I will be acquitted
          when I am tried again." Luetgert went
          Into his cell at 1 p. m., and lying down
          on his cot went to sleep.

          Luetgert, king of the sausage-making
          Industry, has been the object of talk
          and speculation for the last five years.
          His unique personality, his queer hab
          its, his half wild dogs, hjs giant stat
          ure, and the millions of pounds of saus
          age that were carted away from his
          great factory at Dlversey and Hermi
          tage avenues made the Germans and
          Foies of his neighborhood call him a
          king.
          During the twenty years since Luet
          gert and Louise Blckenese were married
          In St. John's Lutheran church, La Salle
          avenue and Ohio street, where her gold
          wedding ring was first worn, Mrs. Luet
          gert had toiled with her husband and
          had planned with him. Luetgert was
          a prosperous saloon keeper when they
          were wedded, and Louise Bickenese was
          a pretty German domestic, who knew
          scarcely a word of English.
          At last Luetgert and his wife had
          saved enough money to buy out a meat
          route, and Luetgert gave up his saloon.
          The family went to live over the mar
          ket, and this prospered better than the
          saloon had done.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1897-12-10/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=-0.268,-0.077,1.535,1.535,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>
          
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063615/1898-01-22/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=-0.264,-0.076,1.528,1.528,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          Oilcngo. Jan. a. A. L. Luetgert went on
          the wltmss stand to-day to tell to the jurj
          his story of the doings in his sausage fac
          tory the night of May L He endeavored to
          explain the mjsterj surrounding tlie dis
          appearance of Ills, wife, for who-e murder
          ha in being tried, hut such tlou piogrcss
          was made that the date of the murdei was
          not reached before the court adjourned.

          Prior to going on the witness stand
          Luetgert, while taking exercise In tl.c jail,
          was accompanied bj James Smith, Who has
          been on trial with Chris Merry for the mur
          der of Merry's wife. Smith was extremely
          nervous over the outcome of the jurj's de
          liberations in his rase, but Luetgei t spoke
          encouragingly to him. 'I received an in
          vitation to a masquerade ball which takes
          plate on February 5." said Luetgert to his
          companion. "I'll let jou have it. 'iou'll
          be able to use It before 1 will."
          Alter relating the storj cf the aiiou3
          llrar.iial deals in which he a. as Interested.
          Luetgert was asked If. during the time
          he was 11m engaged in lm-ines. he was
          married

          At this point Luetgert broke down, and
          commenced crjlng like a child. Seeingjhu
          condition his client was in. Attorney Har
          nian aked for a recess, but Judge Gary
          refused to allow it. After a few moments
          Luetgert regained control of himself.
          The display of grief drew smiles to the
          face of Police Captain Schuettlcr, who oc
          cupied a seat immediately behind "the de
          fendant, and the jurors looked on In as
          tonishment as Luetgert buried nls face
          In his hands and sobbed.
          "Before j ou w ere married, w here did j ou
          and jour little boy Arnold live?" was the
          next question.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1897-12-10/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Adolph+Luetgert+wife&st=text&r=-0.268,-0.077,1.535,1.535,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          SAUSAG MAKER
          WAS CONvcnD 1 l
          Luetgert Jury Brought In a l
          Verdict of Murder 1
          1
          WITH A SENTENCE OF
          LIFE IMPRISONMENT
          Jury on the First Ballot Were
          Unanimous for Conviction i
          1
          On the Exception of the Verdict J
          Luetgert Laughed Does Not R
          gard It Seriously and Is Confident J
          cf a New Trial and Acquittal l J
          1few Spread Like Lightning 1
          Motion for New Trial E
          tered. Chicago Feb 9Adolph L Luetgert
          was tonight convicted of the murder
          of his wife and sentenced to Imprison
          ment in the penitentiary for the term
          of his natural life
          Luetgert received the verdict with a
          laugh.
          At first Luetgert refused to say any
          thing his one response to questions be
          ing I wont talk about It At length
          he yielded to inquiries enough to say
          that the verdict was a surprise to him
          I dont see how the evidence justified
          such a verdict but one thing is sure
          the supreme court will give me a new
          trial and I shall be acquitted
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85033781/1897-10-27/ed-1/?sp=2&q=adolph+luetgert&st=text&r=-0.305,-0.081,1.61,1.61,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
           At this
          roint the story diverges and the most
          erious trouble of A. L. Luetgert's life
          begins. At what hour Mrs. Luetgert
          left the house no one, save possibly her
          husband, knows. The following day
          Sunday members of the family knew
          that its mistress was gone. On the 17th
          day of May the climax came. The saus
          age maker, who had been almost a king
          among his neighbors, was dragged up
          the steps of the East Chicago avenue
          police station at about 2 o'clock In the
          afternoon.

          Luetgert's preliminary examination
          began before Justice Kersten on May
          22. Bickenese, Mrs. Luetgert's L. other,
          told of Luetgert's indifference, old
          Frank Bialk told how Luetgert had
          spent the night on which his wif dis
          appeared cooking something in the rrii
          die vat, and the police disclosed the
          rings. Mrs. Agatha Tosch, Luetgert's
          warm friend and proprietor of the sa
          loon which he patronized most, declared
          to the police she believed him guilty
          cf wife murder, and unexpectedly went
          on the stand and told how Luetgert had
          railed about his wife to her, and had
          eald he wished she were dead.

          Luetgert acknowledged he had suddenly
          recollected this in the office of Luetgert's
          attorneys, and the state flatly charged
          that Luetgert's attorneys had manufact
          ured the evidence.
          Luetgert's threats, his statement that
          he would like to cru?h his wife, and that
          he regreted calling a doctor for her
          when she was ill, that the "dead, rot
          ten boast would have croaKed," were re
          counted by Mrs. Agatha Tosch. Frank
          Bialk told of Luetgert's unexplained
          actions the night his wife vanished, and
          then the state disclosed how the potash
          came in the vat.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87060190/1899-07-28/ed-1/?sp=1&q=adolph+luetgert</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>
        
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85033781/1897-10-27/ed-1/?sp=2&q=adolph+luetgert</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          At what hour Mrs. Luetgert
          left the house no one, save possibly her
          husband, knows. The following day
          Sunday members of the family knew
          that its mistress was gone. On the 17th
          day of May the climax came. The saus
          age maker, who had been almost a king
          among his neighbors, was dragged up
          the steps of the East Chicago avenue
          police station at about 2 o'clock In the
          afternoon.
          Luetgert's preliminary examination
          began before Justice Kersten on May
          22. Bickenese, Mrs. Luetgert's L. other,
          told of Luetgert's indifference, old
          Frank Bialk told how Luetgert had
          spent the night on which his wif dis
          appeared cooking something in the rrii
          die vat, and the police disclosed the
          rings. Mrs. Agatha Tosch, Luetgert's
          warm friend and proprietor of the sa
          loon which he patronized most, declared
          to the police she believed him guilty
          cf wife murder, and unexpectedly went
          on the stand and told how Luetgert had
          railed about his wife to her, and had
          eald he wished she were dead.

          Luetgert acknowledged he had suddenly
          recollected this in the office of Luetgert's
          attorneys, and the state flatly charged
          that Luetgert's attorneys had manufact
          ured the evidence.
          Luetgert's threats, his statement that
          he would like to cru?h his wife, and that
          he regreted calling a doctor for her
          when she was ill, that the "dead, rot
          ten boast would have croaKed," were re
          counted by Mrs. Agatha Tosch. Frank
          Bialk told of Luetgert's unexplained
          actions the night his wife vanished, and
          then the state disclosed how the potash
          came in the vat.

          William Charles, Luetgert's closest
          friend, positively stated he. had helped
          Luetgert dump four barrels of tallow
          and bones In the vat on the night of
          May 1 to make soap with, and other
          witnesses confirmed the claim of the
          defense that Luetgert was making soap
          on the night of May 1.
          Since Luetgert's arrest the claim has
          been made that Mrs. Luetgert has ap
          peared In at least 100 different cities,
          from Nebraska to New York city. Some
          of these were Investigated, and In ev
          ery case but one the defense's assertion
          was exploded. That was the defense's
          claim that Mrs. Luetgert was seen at
          Kenosha, and in the opinion of the state
          It was never shown Mrs. Luetgert was
          there. As many witnesses, and more
          reputable ones, saw the strange woman
          there and were sure she was not Mru.
          Luetgert.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030180/1897-05-30/ed-1/?sp=35&q=adolph+luetgert&st=text&r=-0.222,-0.072,1.444,1.444,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          The tooth that resisted the action of the
          corroding fluid In the vat is a false tooth,
          and Mrs. Luetgert wore just such a false
          tooth, and the dentist who put it there will
          be sought to Identify his handiwork.
          The skull fragments the experts will tell
          are part of a woman's head. The tooth
          identifies this head as Mrs. Luetgert's.
          The State Attorney, if he proves these
          things?and he says he can?will come very
          near raising tbA shadow of Philip Luetgert's
          wife.
          The hair Is of the color and texture of
          the woman's hair. The shadowy skull
          clothed with this assumes still more the
          likeness of Mrs. Luetgert.
          More: The patch of rag, charred and eaten
          by quick lime, is of a piece with the goods
          of the dress worn by Mrs. Luetgert when
          she left her home in her husband's company
          on May 1.

          LUETGERT.
          1
          The Exhibits on the Table.
          The grewsome and meagre fragments
          found in the vats of Adolph Luetgert's
          sausage factory. The State's Attorney
          will try to prove that these are all that
          remains of the rich sausage manufacturer's
          wife. Then he can make his effort
          to convict Luetgert of her murder.
          within the college, they were probably hidden
          in a vault underneath Professor Webster's
          apartments. This vault could be
          reached only by cutting through a thick
          foundation wall of brick.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84022060/1897-08-31/ed-1/?sp=3&q=adolph+luetgert&st=text&r=-0.35,-0.085,1.7,1.7,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>
        
        </text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-boston-corbett</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030313/1865-04-28/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Boston+Corbett</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          On Tuesday afternoon my superior officer, Lieutenant
          Edward P. Docherty, received information that two persons,
          answering to the description of Booth and hts
          accomplice, Harold, were conoealed In a barn on the
          plaoe of Henry Garrett, about three milee from Port
          Royal, In the direction of Bowling Green. There we captured
          a man nam'd Jett, who ferried Booth and his companion
          across the Potomac.

          "I die for my country," and asked those standing by
          to tell hla muthor so. He did not deny his crlnio.
          RKKTUII OK SRttOKAMT BOSTON C0RBR1T.
          Berg-ant Corbett, the soldhr who shot Booth, the
          itvus in, belongs to Company I., Sixteenth New York
          cavalry. Re was born In London, England, In 1S.U, and
          Osi?? to this country when seven years of ago. Ho has
          W Y O
          NEW YORK, FRIDA
          lived In Troy, Now York, where he learned his Undo as
          hat flntaht r, and robeeqnently worked In Albany, Boston,
          Richmond and New York, and enlisted In the latter city
          In the Twelfth New York State Militia, Colonel ButlerHeld.
          While serving under Colonel Bntterfleld he called
          the Colonel to order for swearing. The present Is
          his fourth enlistment

          Corbett Is a regular Oromwelllan
          and a devout Christian. About seven years
          ago he became converted, and joined the Methodist
          Episcopal chnrnh In Boston. Never having been
          baptised, he says he was at a loss what name to adopt,
          and he therefore made it a subiect of nrnver. when Ms
          believed himself Instructed to take the name of Boston,
          the place of his conversion. Be was accordingly baptised,
          upon Joining the ohurcb, Boston; and bis name stands
          upon the muster roll of the company aa Boston Corbett.
        </text>
        </result>
        <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86059181/1865-05-01/ed-1/?sp=1&q=booth+statement+Boston+Corbett</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          W, H. Wbitwobth,
          Lieutenant and Adjutant, Sec'y.
          Statement of the Man who Soot
          Bootn.
          The following is the statement of Ser
          geant Boston Corbett, tbe soldier who
          shot tbe assassin Booth, on Taesday af
          ternoon: "Mr superior officer, Lieut Edward P.
          Dougherty, received information that
          two persous answering to tbe description
          of Booth and his accomplice, Hart-old,
          were concealed in a barn oa the place of
          Henry Garrett, about three miles from
          Port Royal, in the direction of Bowling
          Green. There we captured a man naaied
          Jett, who ferried Booth and hi compan
          ion aero th Potomac. At first be de
          nied knowing anything about th matter,
          but when threatened with death if he did
          not reveal the spot where the assassins
          were seereted, he told us wnere they
          conld be found and pi'.oted us to the
          place. Booth and Harrold reached tha
          barn about desk on Tuesday evening.
          The barn was at once surrounded by our
          cavalry, and eoine of our party engaged
          in conversation with Booth from the out
          side. "He was commanded several time to
          surrender, but made no reply to tbe de
          mand, save that, 'If you want me you
          must take me. When brat asked to sur
          render he asked, 'Who do you take me
          for 7 A short time afterward, in re
          sponse to the question as to whether
          there waa anybody else with him in the
          barn, he itated that he was the only per
          son ia the building tbat his companion,
          liarrold, bad taken another direction,
          and was beyond the reach of capture.
          "At three o clock, or a Utile after, tbe
          barn was fired. Before the flames were
          kindled, Booth had the advantage of us,
          ia respect to light He could see us,
          but we could not see him; but after that
          tbe tables were turned against him we
          could see him plainly, but could not be
          seen by bim. Ibe names appeared to
          confuse him, and he made a spring to
          ward the door, as if to attempt to force
          his way out A he passed by one of
          the crevice of the barn, I fired at him.
          I aimed at his body; did not want to
          kill him; I took deliberate aim at his
          shoulder, but my aim was too high

          Sergeant Corbett, toe soldier woo snot
          Booth, the assassin, belongs to Co. L,
          16th New York cavalry. He was bora
          in London, England, in 1S32, and cam
          ta this country at seven years ol age.
          He has lived in Troy, N. r., where he!
          learned his trade aa a hat finisher, and t
          subsequently worked in Albany, Boston,
          Richmond And New York, and enlisted
          in the latter city. Corbett ia a regular

          It is stated that Booth's horse fell with
          him on the morning of the 15th inst,
          at about the very time the President
          died. 1 He broke his leg below tbe knee,
          Harrold assisted Booth in reaching the
          bouse of Dr. Mudge, at Bryan, on tbe
          road to tbe Patuxent river. He was
          known to be ail right on the secenh ques
          tion. He dressed the wound, after cut
          ting the boot from Booth' a i.-B, and then
          directed Booth to the swamp where he
          secreted himself until Sunday night last,
          when he and Harrold reached Port To
          bacco and crossed tbe PotcmaC in a ca
          noe. In hope of reaching a guerrilla par
          ty near Port Royal. Dr. Madge was ar
          rested some days ago, and the boot taken
          from Booth's leg was found in hi bouse.
          Both are now in the city.
          Upon the person of Booth were found
          bills of exchange on a bank in Canada,
          dated in October last, at the time Booth
        </text>
        </result>
        <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014064/1865-08-29/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Boston+Corbett&st=image&r=-0.112,0,1.224,1.224,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>

        </text>
        </result>
        <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83035144/1865-09-06/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Boston+Corbett&st=text&r=-0.242,-0.074,1.485,1.485,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          The distance rowed was
          four and half miles, and tbe time was twenty-nine
          minutes. The race was eenerallv
          considered as the finest ever rowed In this
          harbor.
          be Boston Poet hasmaJe a very hand
          some spIoS7 to Hadama Campbell, a lady
          described the, Jenkins of thai paper as
          "an Imaginary' Countess" at Saratoga.
          The apology like pthers we have see.i, is
          not in the least benecial to the lady in
          whose behalf jt is
          The Titusville Slaughter, The jury also condemn, in emphatic
          ii!Sk.ftA.f8C'litiee on this road in
          II lliaiiiil ilL j.f tliiiaj.aj
          a judgment in which the entire community
          Boston Corbett.
          Boston Corbett is a character," and no
          mistake. When,' contrary to orders he
          sent a bullet- -whizzing f through Wilkes
          Booth's skull the Iiord directed the shot;
          when the bound in pursuit of him after his
          escape from Andersonville came so near as
          to "rub his nose," the animal was prevent
          ed from biting him by "the same Power
          that kept the lions from tearing Daniel in
          pieces, the same Power in whom I trust".
          We reckon the Commission trying Wirz
          are not far out of the way in deciding to
          throw out Boston's testimony on the ground
          that he is a monomaniac upon the subject
          of the cruelties practiced at Andereonvilla.
          These who have known him from the time
          he used to startle the Methodist prayer
          meetings with his "antics," have been un
          kind enough to suppose him a -monomaniac
          on almost every subject More proper
          ly speaking, Corbett is a religious enthusi
          ast, who entered tbe service from purely
          conscientious motives.

          The
          two turned back, very fortunately for
          themselves, for, as events have
          proved, Corbett' fingers were not pressing
          that trigger for nothing.
          a lew weeks subseqnenfjy the wmrhw
          began to show themselves op the -vallevJ
          and 'detachments of- the Twelfth t aad-
          Twenty-second ware sent to guard the rail.
          roao to rr men ester. uorDett. was ofthn
          Corbett.' was of the'
          nun ber
        </text>
        </result>
        <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045160/1881-03-27/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Boston+Corbett+Booth</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          BOSTON corbett;
          The Man Who killed John Wilkes Booth,
          Pursued by an Avenging iuesis
          His Lire Made a Borden to Him
          The Troubled Spirits of
          Revenge Will 5ot Let
          Him Rest He Is in Constant Fear of As
          sassins, and Though He is a Good
          Man and Faithful Minister He
          (Joes to the Pnlpit with a Pis
          tol by His Side.
          "Private Dalzell" furnishes the Cincin-
          nati Enquirer with the annexed interesting
          reminiscences of Sergeant Boston Corbett,
          the man who killed John ilkes Booth:
          In Monday's issue of the Cincinnati Daily
          Enquirer I find a special dispatch from Wash
          ington setting forth many infesting details of
          tlie Killing ot John Wilkes Booth; but, like
          most of the modern versions- published of
          that tragic event, it leaves "Hamlet" out of
          the play ol llamlet, and omits altogether the
          name of Rev. Boston Corbett, the man who
          killed John Wilkes Booth. I know Boston
          Corbett well. In 1874, when I was holding
          my first experimental national reunion here.
          one of the celebrities of the occasion, whose
          attendance 1 had secured to draw a crowd.
          waj Boston Corbett, He stayed at my house
          here then for a week, and I became inti
          mately acquainted with his remark
          able career, especially that part of
          it wherein he figured as the Ne
          mesis of Booth. General Sherman was
          here the day that Corbett addressed the re
          union, and eyed nun with an eagerness and
          interest that was observed by every soldier
          present, and more than twenty thousand peo
          ple were mat day present at the opening cere
          monies. That day Rev. Boston Corbett
          preached a very eloquent extempore sermon
          from these words: 'The Lord is a man of
          war the Lord is His name." He is a .fiery
          and eloquent speaker, and a devout Christian
          ol the pronounced Methodist type.

           After they had tracked Booth over
          the river and through woods and fields for
          days, at length he was discovered in a barn.
          Corbett saw him in there at the moment the
          straw or hay took fire. The commandfTie
          officer commanded Booth to surrender. He
          was standing, as Corbett saw him through
          the crack in the barn, on a pile of hav, lean
          ing on his crutch, pale with loss of blood
          and from excess of hatred and revenge, for
          John Wilkes Booth never knew what fear
          was. Corbett said he watched Booth like
          hawk. He was standing there on his crutch
          with a carbine in his hand, and had his
          back toward Boston Corbett

          Suddenly Corbett saw Booth
          raise his carbine, as if he were going to
          shoot some one outside, when, quick as light
          ning, Corbett .raised his pistol, fired at the
          Presidenticide, and the next moment he was
          lying on the hay from o tround in exactly the
          tame spof uhere he hit Lincoln. In the next
          second Booth was dragged out, stretched on
          the ground away from the burning barn the
          next he was dead. Corbett told me that
          Booth never spoke after he shot him, and
          that all this nonsense of his dvinjj words was
          mere cinp-M a oi sriibanonarwriicra. ine
          moment the officers saw that Booth was dead
          they inquired for the rash fellow who had
          disobeyed orders, for it was their purpose to
          take him alive and have a grand State trial,
          and all that, after the manner of the great
          histoiic English regicide trials in the time
          of James II. Boston Corbett had spoiled
          that sport. AU eyes turned to Corbett, for
          the soldiers on his side of the barn pointed
          him out as the guilty one, and he was forth
          with placed under arrest. From that hour he
          never knew a moment's peace. The pistol
          with which be killed Booth was stolen from
          him that night, but the holster was left, and
          he had it at my house. His share of the
          prize was likewise stolen frpm him the day
          he irot it verv ceut of it. From the moment
          Corbett killed Booth he was a doomed man.
          One disaster followed another
        </text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85047084/1885-11-23/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Boston+Corbett</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>
            All the rest of the command surren
            dered except Corbett He got in a well
            and refused to give up. He stayed there
            and the well was surrounded, and Mosby
            ordered his men to center their fire on it.
            Corbett fired his forty rounds of car
            tridges, the six shots in his six-shooter
            and four or five cartridges he had in his
            pockets. Then he lay back and
            went to eating his lunch. The
            rebels thought he was dead, and
            for half an hour paid no attention to
            him. Then some one -went up to the
            well-curb, looked over, and there was
            Boston munching hard-tack slowly and
            as unconcerned as if he had been in
            camp. He was hauled out. and spent ten
            months in Andersonville
          </text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn94057006/1885-12-05/ed-1/?sp=3&q=Boston+Corbett</id>
          <rel>0</rel>
          <text>
          
          </text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85032490/1887-02-16/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Boston+Corbett+Booth&st=text&r=-0.267,-0.077,1.533,1.533,0</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>
            At 2 o'clock your reporter found Corbett
            seated in the ladies' gallery gazing down
            upon the members of the house. A seat
            was taken by the side of the man whose
            anger had somewhat subsided but who was
            nervous and regarded even a newspaper
            man treacherously. lie was indeed a dan
            gerous looking man, with a revolver strap
            ped about his person. He would not talk,
            however, and left the reporter seated alone.
            The police were called and after considera
            ble scheming so as to avoid a shooting af
            fray succeeded in capturing the slayer of
            Wilkes Booth, who was taken to the city
            jail where he will await a preliminary trial.
            The general verdict of those who know
            him is that Corbett is deranged.
            Assistant Sergeant at arms George of the
            senate, was raised in the same ward with
            Corbett in the city of Isew York, and says
            that Corbett was orderly and gentlemanly
            when a young man and was an industrious
            hatter by trade, which business he followed
            until he went to the war. It is understood
            that so soon as Boston Corbett w ill quiet
            down, go home and attend to his business
            he will be released and given the money
            due him for services.
          </text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn99021999/1887-10-05/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Boston+Corbett</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>
            Eight permits a.gregatIng.$12,325
            Boston Corbett insane.
            T I'EKA Kath Oct. 2.-Boston Crn-bett
            the man who shot Join Vilkcs lioothi
            the assassin of I'rcsideiit LIncoln was
            last evening declared hopelessly insane
            mmd a guardian was appointed by the
            probate judge tQ take charge of his prop-
            erty. Corbott was taken to the state irt-
            sane asylum 1:11(1 will probably continue
            an inmate of time institution as
            long as ho lives as Jiiysicmafls
            say that it is impossililbie or bun to be
            cured. J'hin story of his blood' deed
            which so effectually blighted his life a'iU
            which has lhmially followed bin into a
            straigint-jacket vilL always be an intorest-
            lug OUC as being nart of a great national
            tragedy. Boston Corbett was an Insignihi-
            cant man at his best but his maine wIll
            always be linked with those of Lincoln
            and Booth and how It became so viil
            vo1l bear repetition.

            After the fire had bee started
            Boston Corbctt stepped up to
            tine barn and through a crevice
            eliot Booth through tine neck. Cor-
            bott fired without orders. lie was
            something of a fanatic ninth for a breach
            of tiseiplino had been court-mailed and
            sentenced to be eliot. Tine order however
            over was not executed but lie had tcen
            drummed out of the regiment. While
            living in Boston Mass
          </text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016014/1905-09-22/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Boston+Corbett</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>
              he has not had time to go over
              the evidence and a postponement of
              one week was found necessary.
              NOT REAL BOSTON CORBETT.
              Man Under Arrest at San Angelo Is
              an Impostor.
              Sergeant John Gardiner returned
              this morning from San Angelo, Tex.,
              where he was subpoenaed as a wit
              ness against a man claiming to be the
              only and original Boston Corbett,
              slayer of J. Wilkes Booth.
              The man had attempted to secure a
              pension under the name of Boston
              Corbett, and was on -trial before the
              federal court. His defense was in
              sanity, but he was bound over.
              Gardiner says that the impostor "s
              the same man who advertised himself
              as Boston Corbett in Oklahoma two
              years ago. Gardiner was called upon
              at that time to identify the man.
              The real Boston Corbett is supposed
              to be dead, as he has not been seen-
              by any one who couia positively
              identify him in many years. He was
              adjudged insane in Topeka in 1897,
              and escaped from the asylum a few
              weeks later. The charge of insanity
              was the result of an outbreak during
              the session of the legislature. Corbett
              was a doorkeeper, and becoming sud
              denly insane, adjourned the house
              with a pair of large revolvers instead
              of a gavel..
              Gardiner assisted in the arrest of
              Corbett at that time, and says that he
              would know him anywhere.
              The impostor who was tried at San
              Angelo is a large man, while the real
              Boston Corbett was a very small, wild
              looking man.
          </text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86090528/1901-11-13/ed-1/?sp=3&q=lincoln%E2%80%99s+avenger</id>
          <rel>0</rel>
          <text>
          
          </text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038411/1918-07-17/ed-1/?sp=3&q=lincoln%E2%80%99s+avenger&st=text&r=-0.193,-0.005,1.385,1.385,0</id>
          <rel>0</rel>
          <text>
          
          </text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn91064009/1908-08-11/ed-1/?sp=6&q=lincoln%E2%80%99s+avenger</id>
          <rel>0</rel>
          <text>
          
          </text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83016586/1920-11-19/ed-1/?sp=2&q=lincoln%E2%80%99s+avenger</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>
            Washington, revered as the father I
            of our country, wah the target of I
            the most scurrilous attacks. Lin
            cojii, loved of al men in 1920, was
            a fiend in 1865. Scorned by his own
            cabinet, branded as a traitor and an j
            autocrat, he was finally murdered by
            “an avenger of the people.”
            Lincolns Gettysburg speech, impee-;
            cab e in its English and lofty in its i
            sentiment, was termed by a newspa
            per of that time a partisan politcal
            preachment.
          </text>
        </result>
        <result>
          <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83020847/1895-09-27/ed-1/?sp=4&q=lincoln%E2%80%99s+avenger</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>
            Abraham Lincoln's avenger-
            CORBETT, WHO KILLED BOOTH.
            IntcrrMiing Reminiscence* of n Holyoke
            .Unn of ihc MerRCHUI Who Nhot the
            A»*n«*iu of the Isoved Prewidenl.
            One figure in American history has had
            little recognition, chiefly because there were
            so many other stirring events at the limp
            he played his part. When Booth, President
            Lincoln’s assassin, was discovered in a barn
            a distance out of Washington, Boston Cor
            liett was one of the soldiers there eager to
            take him. The barn was set on fire and it
            was seen that in a short time the murderer
            would have to show himself. He was
            maimed by the broken leg that he had re
            ceived when he jumped from the box in the
            theater after shooting the president, but he
            was still determined and game. He was
            armed with a carbine and had already shot
            two men in the punming party. He w’ould
            not surrender, but when he did appear he
            threatened to kill every one he could hit.
            Sergeant Corbett was in front of the barn,
            BOSTON CORBETT,
            THE MAN WHO KILLED BOOTH.  There
            were those who were more anxious to
            avenge the death of Booth than Corbett had
            been to avenge that of President Lincoln.
            But he was aide to avoid all danger and
            was discharged in due time. He went to
            N®r York erty and remained there a num
            ber of years, working at his trade. He then
            drifted West and was appointed sergeant
            at-arms in the state capitol of Kansas.
          </text>
        </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-chicago-black-sox-scandal</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88078751/1919-10-10/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Inning+Runs+Cincinnati+Opened+SERIES+Four+Game+WORLD+First</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
    Cincinnati Opened The Game By Making Four Runs In The
    First Inning; Five Hits Were Made By the Red Slug
    gers; One Half An Inning Was Sufficient For Williams
    Who Retired In Favor Of James.
    (BY THE ASSOCIATED PRESS TO THE BANNER)
    COAUSKEY PAJtK, CHICAGO, J 11., Oct. 9 The sun
    roke through .tho heavy clouds shortly before noon but an
    extremely high wind'slming which gave promise of inter
    fering with the fielding end of the contest. The bleachers
    and pavilions were tilled long before tim for the game and
    indications were for a record crowd. Clouds of dust were
    raised by the wind swooping down upon the diamond.
    A
    The line-up:
    Cincinnati Chicago
    Rath, 2nd. Leibold, c.f.
    Daubert, 1st. Kddlo Collins, 2nd.
    Groh, 3rd. Weaver, 3d.
    Roush, c.f. Jackson, l.f.
    Duncan, l.f. Felsch, r.f.
    Kopf, s.s. Gandll, 1st.
    Neale. r.f. Risberg, s.s.
    Rariden, c. Schalk, c.
    Kller.i). Williams, p.
    x James, .p..
    x Relieved Williams in first.
    Game By Innings
    First Inning
    CINCINNATI Rath up. Strike one.
    The first Uail pitched oy Williams
    split the plate but Rath did not make
    a bid lor it. Stiike two. It was a
    ioul. itath opened the contest witu a
    J pop fly that Kisberg got in short left.
    Daubeit up. Stiike one. Daubert
    singled to center. It was a line drive
    thai Leibold made a great effort for,
    but could not uulte reach befoie it
    touched tho ground. Groh up. Strike
    lone.

    Ball two.
    Eller ended the Inning by 11 lug out
    to Felsch. FOUR RUNS, FIVE HITS,
    NO ERRORS.
    The Rods displayed the most con
    secutive hitting of the series in this
    inning. Third Inning
    CINCINNATI Duncan up. Strike
    one. Weaver took Duncan's high
    bounder and threw him out at first.
  
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1919-12-16/ed-1/?sp=14&q=Insists+Comiskey+Put+Sox+Efforts+Forth+Best</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
    When a man plays the best golf in a tournament from Saturds
    through Saturday, when in the final stretch he is able to play thirty-tv
    holes two better than 4's over one of the most rugged tests in the realm
    golf, there is no great question as to how he has met the test. Herri
    had to be at his best to beat Bobby Jones, for the Atlanta youngster he
    on grimly the greater part of the way against putting exhibitions th;
    would have broken the soul of the normal contender.
    But there wasn't a period where Herron developed the slightest atta<
    of nerves.

    I Comiskey Insists Sox
    Put Forth Best Efforts
    CHICAGO. Dec. l?r>. Rumors that
    several members of the White Sox did
    not put forth their best efforts ?lurir.J
    the world's series were denied to-day
    by President Charles Comiskey.
    Comiskey, who said he had investi"
    i gated the rumors since the report?
    were first heard at the close of the
    series, declared he has found no in?
    dication of "double crossing" by any
    of the players.


  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1920-09-24/ed-1/?sp=20&q=White+Sox</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
    With the gand jury adjourned until
    next Tuesday, baseball magnates and
    fan are watchtne the White Sox, for
    their Tictory or defeat lu the series
    with the league-icsatnp; inuians u
    Cleveland may decide the future course
    of the Investigation. If the White Sox
    win today they will displace Cleveland
    and lH thi Ipninip bv half a game
    nan Johnson, president of the Amer- (A&u&l tfi
    kan League, is reported to have received I numro Cle
    rumors that gamblers are trying io
    create an impression that the White
    Eox do not daro win the league pen
    nant. According to statements quot
    ing Mr. Johnvm published by papers
    here, the syndicate of gamblers which.
    It has been charged, "bought" Inst
    year's world series by paying 100.
    OOO to five white Sox players, threatens
    to expose the plot If the Chicago team
    wins the race.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1920-09-25/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Jury+Series+Fixer+Grand+World+Finds</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
    Grand Jury
    Finds World
    Series 'Fixer'
    Foreman Says Man Who
    Acted for Gamblers and
    Made Offers to White
    Sox Players Is Known
    Only Few Players
    Involved in Fraud
    aArnold Rothstein, William
    Burns and Abe Attell
    To Be Called to Testify
    CHICAGO, Sept. 24.?H. H. Brigham,
    foreman of the Cook County Grand
    Jury investigating alleged baseball
    gambling, to-night told newspaper men
    that the name of the man who "fixed''
    the 1919 world's series for Cincinnati
    to win had been given to the grand
    jury. This man, Brigham stated, acted
    a:? a representative of a ring of gam?
    blers, who offered Chicago White Sox
    players money to throw games to the
    Cincinnati Reds.
    Brigham declared that the testimony
    thus far given had caused the grand
    jury to decide to subp?nae Arnold
    Rothstein, of New York, millionaire
    turfman and controlling owner of the
    Havre do Grace racetrack; William
    Burns, former Chicago American and
    Cincinnati National League pitcher;
    Abe Attell, former featherweight box
    ing champion, and several other well
    known sportsmen.
    Earlier in the day Mr. Brigham is- i
    sued a statement declaring positively
    that there had been "crooked work" in j
    organized baseball, and setting forth j
    the intention of the Cook County grand
    jury to get to the bottom of it.
    At the same time "Charles A. I
    Comiskey, owner of the White Sox, in
    a statement criticized Ban Johnson,
    president of the American League, for
    failure to cooperate in the investiga-
    tion of chargcj? of crookedness leveled
    against the Chicago teams.
    These were the happenings to-day
    ^following the adjournment yesterday;
    until Tuesday of the grand jury. Other j
    features of the day -re:
    Announcement that the grand jury j
    would not be dissolved on September
    30, but would be retained as a special
    inquisitorial body to probe further the
    charges of crookedness in baseball.
    Sensational charges by Rube Benton,
    pitcher for the New York Giants.
    that a pool of $100,000 was paid to cer
    tain White Sox players by a Pittsburgh I
    gambling syndicate for the ''throwing"
    of the world series between the Chi-
    cago White Sox and the Cincinnati
    Beds.
    After Gambling Syndicates
    Indications that the grand jury in- j
    vestigation would reach out and em
    brace the activities of the so-called j
    gambling syndicates whose sinister in- i
    fluences are said to have been at work
    in certain games.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1920-09-29/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Indicted+indicted+Eight+eight+Sox+White</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
    Mrs. Bergdoll, Braun, Albert S. Mit?
    chell and Charles Schuh were found
    guilty on the second indictment of
    conspiracy with each other, the jury
    recommending mercy for Mitchell and
    Schuh.
    On individual indictments of aiding
    the convicted draft dodgers, Mrs. Berg-'
    cjoll, Braun and Romig were found
    guilty, while a verdict of not guilty
    was returned for Mitchell and Schuh.
    Mrs. Bergdoll faces a term of 32
    years in Federal prison and a fine of
    $30,000 as the maximum penalty that
    the court might fix. For Romig the
    extreme punishment might be eight
    years' imprisonment and $14,000 fine,
    Braun, who changed his name from
    Bergdoll after his brothers attained
    their notoriety, may go to prison for
    seven years and $10,000 fine. Mitchell
    and Schuh might be fined $10,000 and
    go to prison for two years each. The
    indictments for the quintet included 56
    counts in nine bills.
    
    Eight White Sox Are Indicted;
    Cicotte and Jackson Confess
    Gamblers Paid Them $15,000
    Attell Angry,
    Will Expose
    Series Plot
    Ex Pugilist Declares
    He'll "Raise the Lid
    Sky High" With Story
    of Deal at the Astor
    Abe Attell, the former featherweight
    champion, was angry yesterday when
    he learned that Billy Maharg accused
    him of "fixing" last year's world's
    series with $100,000 at the Hotel Astor.
    There was a deal at the Astor, he said,
    and he'd "shoot the lid sky high" with
    the story of it soon, but he was not a
    party to it. He accused Arnold Roth
    stein of naming him in connection
    with it.
    Jacob Ruppert and T. L. Huston,
    owners of, the Yankees, telegraphed to
    Charles A. Comiskey, owner of the
    I White Sox, that he could take his pick
    I of their men to fill the gaps caused
    j by his suspension of the White Sox
    players who were Indicted.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1920-09-30/ed-1/?sp=15&q=ATTELL+MAY+ABE+CITY</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
    ABE ATTELL MAY
    BE IN THIS CITY
    Former Prlzofightor, Mentioned
    in Basobatl Scandal, Said
    to Havo Como Horo
    Abe Attell, the former featherweight
    champion of the world, and now one of
    the central fljrurcs In the bnsebnll scan
    dal expose, is reported to bo "come
    where In rhtlndclphla" todny. Attell
    lit Eeeking seclusion from his usual
    haunts In Nftw York nud also confer
    rlntc with his attorneys In view of pef
    tilxtent rumors that ho 1h to bo brought
    directly into tho expose by tho Chicago
    grand Jury.
    Attell hns been named freely by the
    'hlte Sox who have confessed to tak
    ing bribes to "throw" tho last world's
    series as tho "go between" for the
    gambling clique.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1920-10-01/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Plot+Ball+Proof</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
  
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1921-03-17/ed-1/?sp=12&q=Owner+Sox+White+Terminates+Contracts</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
    Owner of White Sox Terminates Contracts Existing
    at Time of Suspension
    f'HICA60, March 10.?Charles Comiskey, president of the Chicago
    j .American League baseball club, to-day severed all relations with seven
    j While Sox players connected with the 1919 World's Series scandal. These
    j men are now under grand jury indictments, and a date for their trial will
    be set to-morrow.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1921-07-22/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Series+Players+Burns+Idea+Plot&r=-0.079,0.337,1.133,0.613,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
    I
    Burns Calls
    Series Plot
    Players' Idea
    ??____
    Testifies First Proposal
    Came From Gcotte and
    Gandil Court Rules
    I N. Y. Talks Admissible
    State Scores in
    Conspiracy Charge
    j Witness Admits Mistake
    in Account of Meeting
    After Opening Game
    Special Disvateh to The Tribune
    CHICAGO, July 21.--Judge Friend
    this evening decided that conversations
    held in New York between Cicotte,
    Gandil, Bill Burns and Attell before the
    1919 world series opened would be ad?
    mitted in the records of the trial of
    the indicted ball players and gamblers
    l growing out of the "throwing" of the
    games. Twice before the judge had
    ruled that these conversations were not
    admissible, but to-day, after the state
    had insisted that it had proved the ex?
    istence of a conspiracy by the testi?
    mony of Bill Burns, it was decided to
    admit the conversations. This is a de?
    cided victory for the state.
    Another important development was
    the statement by Burns that it was not
    the gamblers, but the ball players, who
    conceived the plot of juggling the
    world series. He testified that Cicotte
    and Gandil had come to him in Now
    jYork with a proposition to "throw" the
    i series for $100,000. Burns also brought
    in the names of Jean Dubu?

    Burns Admit?? Misstatemcnts
    Give and take exchange of personal?
    ities to-day enlivened the closing hours j
    of the inquisition to which Burns, the
    state's star witness in the baseball
    trial, has been subjected since he fin?
    ished his direct testimony yesterday.
    The defence attorneys after having
    examined him by batteries and in?
    dividually, finally abandoned the at?
    tack, unable to upset the principal por?
    tions of his testimony. In the morning
    session Burns admitted that he had
    made misstatemcnts regarding certain
    meeting? with the White Sox players
    in the Sinton Hotel in Cincinnati.
    Attorney Benedict J. Short, who
    closed the examination for the defense,
    questioned Burns concerning his trans?

    i Attorney Nash, who opened the
    cross-examination when Burns re- i
    I sumed the stand at the beginning of j
    I the morning session, occupied him-
    I self principally with questions re?a-
    tive to the alleged meeting of Burns
    with Chicago players in the Sinton
    Hotel prior to the first game of the
    series in Cincinnati.
    Burns admitted that he had not
    arrived in Cincinnati until 10 a. m.
    the day of the first game and that he
    had not reached the hotel until 11
    o'clock.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1921-07-23/ed-1/?sp=10&q=Chicago+series+Series+BLACK+Black+Sox+SOX</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
  
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042344/1912-02-23/ed-1/?sp=6&q=abe+attell</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
    A pew fi utli-I Wellflil chain
    pinn waa proclaimed hero today wh-n
    Jobnn) Kill, an. i of Cleveland, Ohio,
    i b al ly outfought outgnmed and out
    slugged Abe Attell, th hithettu In
    vinolble champion,
    K Ibani a Victory was clear cut and
    decisive.
    Ha hgd tha I tt-r of al the rounds
    with the possible exception of two.
    He left the ring with one mark over
    hie eye, where Audi butted him with
    his head. Attell was badly brulsei.
    Mine thousand persona ettnaaoed
    the tight.

    They clinched again and Attell miss
    ed a light kmind even.
    Round 2 Bach man tried to fee'
    out his opponent Kllbana put a vfc
    loua left to the Jaw and avoided a
    left counter. Attell did not seem as
    Cast on his teat ns Klrhane. The
    Clevelander landed right and left and
    ivoided returns. He brought Wood
    frmn Attel!'a inniith with u .straight
    left Kllbana again landed two hard
    lefts to tho fact, starting the blood
    flowing, A rlgh: tn Attell s bad eye
    nearly closed tha optic, it was KUr
    barn 's round.
    Hound 3 -They clinched and Kll
    bana complained to the refereo that
    Attell bent his arm. Attell held on
    and at the break dodged a vlejottl
    lefl only to encounter a hard right.
    Back man was fighting rapidly and
    rmightly. In the next clinch Attell
    was warned for "heeling." Kllbana
    put right and left to tho face. The
    bell ring with tho man Clinched.
    Kllbane'a round.
    Kilbniie was first to enter the ring,
    lb- climbed thrnugh tho ropes al
    1 11 and was greeted with wild cheer
    ing, lie wore green trunks. Attell
    limbed Into the ring at 3:1" and
    araa scarcely noticed by the specta
    tors, lb-spite the fact that ho was a
    2 to 1 favorite In the betting.
    Attell and Kllbana met al one side'
    nf the ring and Attell "lushed" the
    Cleveland lad becraee of his green
    trunks.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn78000090/1955-11-04/ed-1/?sp=7&q=abe+attell</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
  
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn91064009/1909-02-20/ed-1/?sp=7&q=abe+attell</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
    JEM DRISCOLL DEFEATS ABE ATTELL
IN TEN ROUNDS AT NATIONAL A. C.
I WHAT DRISCOLL DID J
TO ABE ATTELL. t
4* Driscoll landed four blows to X
4 Attell's one. X
4 Driscoll was the better at long X
4 ru nge. X
4 Driscoll did the better in-fighting, a.
4 Driscoll s footwork was the better, a.
4 Driscoll’s ducking was superior to X
4 Attell’s. X
4 Driscoll had the better of eight X
4 of the ten rounds. x
4 Driscoll's double Jab had Attell X
4 scared. X
4 Driscoll blackened Attell's right X
4 iye so he couldn’t see. X
4 Driscoll's lighting was cleaner 4
4 than his opponent's. 4
4 Driscoll was just as strong as 4
4 Attell at the finish. 4
44444444444444444444444444
Englishman Has Better of CalU
fornian in Most Scientific
Battle Ever Seen.
Jem Driscoll, the English champion,
won the featherweight championship of
the world at the National A. C. last
night by clearly outpointing Abe Attell
In a sensational ten-round bout before
a wildly excited crowd. Driscoll out
pointed Attell In surprisingly easy form,
the Briton using his left Jab and his
marvelous ducking ability to the utter
astonishment of Attell. In fact, at
times Driscoll flashed around Attell at
ouch a clip that the California cham
pion was too astonished to do anything
but gasp at the Engishman’s quickness.
Both boys fought an extremely care
ful fight, each studying the other In
cautious manner and leaving but very
few openings for the other to take ad
vantage of. But It was left-hand work
which paved the way for Driscoll.
Once getting his left working rightly,
he soon found a landing place on Attell,
and, finding that Abe was unable to
stop these slinging Jabs, Jem never let
up an Instant in forcing the fighting.
He was In and out like a flash, Jabbing,
dancing away and then ducking the At
tell rushes with a nimbleness of foot
which bewildered the spectators. Abe
tried hard to shoot a right over in the
clinches, but every time Driscoll blocked
that wallop by quick covering up and
holding whenever Attell tried to swing
or shot up his right.

two lefts to jaw. Jem slowed up a too
ment, then came back with two sharp
lefts on face. Attell's left went to stomach j
and Driscoll planted a good left on At
tell’s wind. Driscoll landed left twice on
the eye. Attell hooked a left on car, then
put two light lefts on the face. Jem
smashed Attell’s eye at the bell. Attell's
round.
Round 7—Attell's left was blocked, but
his right went solid on Jem’s ear Driscoll
came back with a left on nose. Attell pnt
ft left on nose, then to the law. staggering
Driscoll. Attell battered the stomach and
Jem jabbed left to the mouth. Attell sent
a right to the heart. Driscoll walloped the
i kidneys, then seat three lefts to tile eye,
nose and mouth. Attell’s round.
Round 8—‘Attell’s left was blocked and
Jem Jabbed left, on mouth Attell landed
a left and right on bend. tb*>n a swap of
lefts on face was followed by Jem with
a left to Attell's chin and a right on ear.
Attell put a left to Jaw and crossed a good
right on ear. Driscoll darted two lefts
to face. Attell replied with a left and
rlgbi. Jeui was short with a left, lot
after Attell got to the eye with left
Driscoll landed two lefts lightly on face.
Attell pnt two to the stomach with both
hands and they were locked at the bell
Honors even
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn78000090/1955-11-04/ed-1/?sp=7&q=abe+attell&st=text&r=-0.338,-0.084,1.676,1.676,0</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
  
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn91064009/1909-02-20/ed-1/?sp=7&q=abe+attell&st=text&r=-0.252,-0.075,1.504,1.504,0</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
    Jem Driscoll, the English champion,
won the featherweight championship of
the world at the National A. C. last
night by clearly outpointing Abe Attell
In a sensational ten-round bout before
a wildly excited crowd. Driscoll out
pointed Attell In surprisingly easy form,
the Briton using his left Jab and his
marvelous ducking ability to the utter
astonishment of Attell. In fact, at
times Driscoll flashed around Attell at
ouch a clip that the California cham
pion was too astonished to do anything
but gasp at the Engishman’s quickness.
Both boys fought an extremely care
ful fight, each studying the other In
cautious manner and leaving but very
few openings for the other to take ad
vantage of. But It was left-hand work
which paved the way for Driscoll.
Once getting his left working rightly,
he soon found a landing place on Attell,
and, finding that Abe was unable to
stop these slinging Jabs, Jem never let
up an Instant in forcing the fighting.
He was In and out like a flash, Jabbing,
dancing away and then ducking the At
tell rushes with a nimbleness of foot
which bewildered the spectators. Abe
tried hard to shoot a right over in the
clinches, but every time Driscoll blocked
that wallop by quick covering up and
holding whenever Attell tried to swing
or shot up his right.
Round 1—Driscoll was short with his left
and Attell ripped left and right to the
wind. Driscoll’s left went to face three
times and Attell sent left to wlud and
crowded Jem to the ropes. Attell misses
two swings as Driscoll sidesteps and the
American falls against the ropes. He
bounded back laughing. He hit Jem with
a left to the stomach. Jem’s lightning left
found Attell’s mouth. It was DriscoIl'H
round.

Jem- staggered Attell with a
f?UdJlK|}ts0n th0 3aw' Attell rushed, but
To?iJ!Ln8 Sh.man d’,lcked of harm's way.
5SK.°H..put two u’ftK to AtteU's face t*id
h m KP, wlfh "Oita right on ear
£tt®tj reached Abe stomach with both
Pa5d.Bc dem cnt Attell’s eye with a left
aad then put the left to the wind. After a
break they exchanged lefts on the mouth.
Driscoll s left went to Attell's nose and to
the mouth. Driscoll's round
Round 5—Attell Jabbed left to the nose
and Jem put Attell to the ropes with a
left on ear. Driscoll hit Attell on the ear
with a right swing. They swapped lefts on
the head ana when Attell ducked a swing
Driscoll sent one to the kidneys. Jem's
.rft shot to the face and then
attell jarred Jem with a stiff left on the
jaw. Both landed short-arm lefts on head
uid, after a clinch, Jpiu sent left to the
bad eye and nose.

Round 7—Attell's left was blocked, but
his right went solid on Jem’s ear Driscoll
came back with a left on nose. Attell pnt
ft left on nose, then to the law. staggering
Driscoll. Attell battered the stomach and
Jem jabbed left to the mouth. Attell sent
a right to the heart. Driscoll walloped the
i kidneys, then seat three lefts to tile eye,
nose and mouth. Attell’s round.
Round 8—‘Attell’s left was blocked and
Jem Jabbed left, on mouth Attell landed
a left and right on bend. tb*>n a swap of
lefts on face was followed by Jem with
a left to Attell's chin and a right on ear.
Attell put a left to Jaw and crossed a good
right on ear. Driscoll darted two lefts
to face. Attell replied with a left and
rlgbi. Jeui was short with a left, lot
after Attell got to the eye with left
Driscoll landed two lefts lightly on face.
Attell pnt two to the stomach with both
hands and they were locked at the bell
Honors even
Round D—Driscoll rocked Attell’s head
with a left on mouth and Attell staggered
Jein with two left hooks on the Jaw. Jem
sent left to nose lightly and then to the
mouth. Attell 
  </text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
